LEO ALLEN

TECHNICAL CONSULTANT, WEB DEVELOPER

Profile

From helping start-ups get off the ground to working in large teams for established websites with millions of users, I have over 10 years experience creating, developing, designing and advising for companies in four continents in all aspects required to make a successful online business.

Skills

Web Development

Specialising in Ruby, PHP, and Javascript I'm passionate about not just coding, but finding the elusive balance between doing something the right way using everyone's favourite acronyms (TDD, OOP, MVC, etc.) and getting it delivered on time and on budget.

Project Direction

Experience in managing, directing and training teams, ensuring that team members are happy, engaged and productive, and implementing best practices such as Agile - or even better Extreme Programming (XP) - to get the job done effectively with as little time wasted on pointless managerial procedures.

Product Development

I believe the key to web development is communication, and most importantly this is ensuring that the business goals and the technical needs are working together nicely. That's why I've found my most successful projects have been those in which I've been allowed to give technical insights into the direction of the business/product.

Technical

Ruby/Rails	Javascript/CoffeeScript	РНР
HTML5	CSS ₃	Git
Unix	MySQL/PostgreSQL	Some experience of NodeJS/Python

Selected Experience

Makers Academy

Senior Engineer/Coach

2014-2016

Returned to Makers Academy (Europe's largest coding bootcamp) to lead up the Engineering team, introducing best practices such as Continuous Integration/Deployment, XP-themed Agile, TDD, pair programming, etc. Helped update the curriculum with Node.js and Angular.js, and coached hundreds of students into their first job. Worked on product design, introducing Design Sprints and doing proper UX with user interviews and metrics. Helped the team experiment with self-management, and introduced ideas of self-management into the engineering team.

Various

Freelance Web Developer

2014

Worked on a wide variety of projects: everything from a Chaplin.js/Backbone.js/Rails based booking management system, to a custom-designed interactive map using Leaf.js/Mapbox and Drupal, to a music visualizer for the London Symphony Orchestra built in tandem with an animator using Blender and Python.

Enternships

Lead Developer

2013-2014

Acted as interim Lead Developer for a socially-minded jobs board for young people. Assisted in the rebuilding from scratch of the website in Rails, introducing a strict BDD-based approach to code development, whilst overseeing a more agile system of team management.

ECPAT International

Web Designer/Technical Consultant

2013

Advised Bangkok-based international charity with subsidiaries in over 70 countries on the direction they should take technically. Following this consultancy volunteered to rebuild and redesign their current site, and based on a thorough research of their user's and the charities needs built a Drupal site with a cleaned-up, stripped-down design.

Maker's Academy

Teacher

2013

Founding member of the faculty of a 12-week intensive web development course, both taught students in the class and assisted with the development of the curriculum. Students have since gone on to work at companies such as Sky and LastMinute.com

CouchSurfing.org

Software Engineer

2011-2012

Worked on one of the largest and well-established travel websites (with over 6 million registered users), both on over-hauling the current site, creating a new events system, as well as being entrusted with architecting and building the API for their mobile apps.

Mukuru.com

Lead Developer

2008-2010

Architected and built an entire mobile money-transfer system - the same system is still being used four years on and and has transferred over \$1 billion using an innovative SMS-based approach. Included in the system was a custom-built accounting application, anti-fraud protection, CRM and more.

Various Companies

Freelance Web Developer

2004-2014

For the past 10 years I have worked freelance on-and-off for various companies, doing everything from building a co-working website in Ruby for a New-York based start-up to a bill-sharing application written in PHP.

Education

First Class Honours in Intellectual and Cultural History, University of Sussex